# Sandesh Wadal

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

## **Profile**

Mobile App developer with around 7+ experience. Worked on **React-Native**, **iOS**, Android. Involved in brainstorming sessions for the business process. Involved in solution designing and fit-gap analysis. Integrated Unit testing for applications.

Ability to always look for ways to improve performance as well as readability of the code.

## **Employment History**

#### Senior Software Developer, Cognizant Technology Solutions, Pune

JANUARY 2019 - PRESENT

- Developed multiple apps on iOS and Android using React-Native.
- Developed HOC and reusable code for better Products.
- Worked with Native bridge to implement native code in React-Native apps.
- Worked with different libraries to integrate functionalities like Authentication, analytics, and push notifications.
- Directed software design and development across multifaceted team to meet client needs for functionality, timeline and performance.

#### React-Native Developer, FIGmd, Pune

FEBRUARY 2018 - DECEMBER 2018

- Implemented dynamic rendering of forms.
- Used the Mingo library for validations.
- Implemented Jest for snapshot testing.
- Increased customer satisfaction by resolving Product issues.

#### IOS Application Developer, Ivitesse (division Of Rsb Group), Pune

DECEMBER 2016 - FEBRUARY 2018

- Implemented drawing on map.
- Drawing different shapes on map (Arrow, circle, polygon).
- Implementation of radaeepdf PDF editing library for iOS.
- · Added annotations, bookmark, highlighting of text in pdf.

#### Director and iOS Developer, Coblence IT Solutions Pvt Ltd, Pune

AUGUST 2015 - SEPTEMBER 2016

- Ownership of the product (GoaBikes).
- Design of the app Workflow for the app
- Worked closely with organizational leadership, including the board of directors, to strategically affect the direction of operations.

#### iOS Developer, Apheleia Solutions Pvt. Ltd, Pune

JULY 2013 - MAY 2015

- Worked well independently and on a team to solve problems.
- Implemented text to voice functionality.
- Implemented different targets for 6 languages in a single project.
- TTS Based application used Loquendo voices, Modeltalker voice, Nuance Voice.
- Writepad SDK Implementation.
- Implemented YouTube search.

#### **Details**

Pune

India

08208069367

sandesh.wadal@gmail.com

NATIONALITY

Indian

DATE OF BIRTH

03/01/191

#### Links

Linkedin

#### **Skills**

React-Native

**JavaScript** 

Objective C

Swift

React js

Android

Mobile Application
Developement

#### **Hobbies**

Hiking, Trekking, Travelling

### Languages

English

Hindi

Marathi

- Implemented Predictions for keyboard-based on the UK, US, and Topical dictionaries.
- Facebook, Twitter, Dropbox integration.

## **Education**

### PG Diploma, Sunbeam Institute Of Information, Pune

AUGUST 2012 - FEBRUARY 2013

Wireless And Mobile Communication.

### Bachelor's Degree, G.H.Raisoni College Of Engineering, Nagpur

AUGUST 2008 - MAY 2012

**Electronics And Communications Engineering** 

## **Tools**

VS Code, Xcode, Android Studio, Git.